Vineet Patil

Software Engineer

Summary

Software Development Engineer with over 6 years of hands-on experience in various software development roles. Able to utilize a wide array of technologies while participating in the development of new applications and software-based functionality. Strong Object oriented programming and design skills. Experienced working in agile software development environment.

• Specialties:

Programming Skills: Java, C, C++, Android, QT Library, Shell script, Perl, XML, SQL, JUnit, JMock, Spring Development Platforms: Unix, Microsoft Windows, Mac OSX, Android, Kindle Fire Phone and Tablet SDK, Amazon AWS SQS, SWF, S3, DynamoDB

Tools: Eclipse, Visual Studio, Kindle Fire SDK, XCode, Fortify, Git, Perforce, SVN.

Experience

Software Engineer at Microsoft

October 2016 - Present

Working on Skype for Business's Mobile Application Platform for Android, iOS and MacOSX.

Software Engineer at Cyanogen

September 2015 - October 2016 (1 year 2 months)

- Working on Mod Platform. Design and implement features and APIs to enable richer, intelligent and contextually aware experiences built directly into OS https://mod.life/mods.
- Work with our partners to enable their feature experiences on Cyanogen OS.
- Work on several applications for Cyanogen OS. Implementing new features for Messaging, Dialer, Telephony and Launcher applications.
- Support and maintain applications for Cyanogen OS by fixing bugs.

Software Development Engineer at Amazon

June 2011 - September 2015 (4 years 4 months)

- Designed and developed Kindle Docs application for Fire Phone and Fire tablets. Kindle Docs application allows users to access and manage their personal documents and Cloud Drive documents on their kindle devices. [Java, Android, XML, Fire phone SDK, Fire Tablet SDK]
- Responsible for improving performance and fluidity of Kindle Docs application for Fire phone. Improved application fluidity and performance from 4800ms (cold start time) to 1350ms.
- Worked on back-end systems for Kindle Personal Documents program to manage customer's personal documents and ensure their secure delivery to customer's kindle devices and kindle applications. [Java]

- Designed and developed Amazon Send to Kindle application for PC, Mac OSX, Web and Mobile platforms. Send to kindle application enables the customers to directly share their personal documents with their Kindle devices. [C++, QT library, Shell script, Apple Script, Java, Android]
- Mentored new SDEs and interns in the team and provided guidance in their projects.

Graduate Student at Georgia Institute of Technology

July 2009 - June 2011 (2 years)

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

Harnessing Network and System Call traces for Malware Analysis: [Developed on Xen using Java, Shell script, PostgreSQL]

- Implemented a tool for complete automation of Ether (a Malware analysis tool based on Hardware Virtualization).
- Built a database of malware activity based on Windows native system call traces and network activity.

Secure Distributed File System SDFS: [Java]

- Developed a file System which stores copies of users' files on client machines in encrypted format.
- The system provides clients with delegation facility which enables one user to delegate authority over resources to another user. Also provided facility to revoke authority.

Thread Scheduling with GTThreads: [C]

- Implemented work conserving credit and lottery-based schedulers for user-level SMP GTThreads library.
- Performed migration of user threads using the principles of work conservation and load balancing.

Shared Inter-Process Service: [C]

- Implemented a complete inter process service using shared memory based on Xen VMM design.
- Implemented a domain that can be accessed by any process on the system.

GT FTP Monitor: [C, Vsftpd]

- Implemented an additional layer of security over Vsftpd ftp server.
- Implemented Role Based Access Control (RBAC) policy over files accessed.

SIPhon: [Java, Php, Shell script, Festival TTS, Sphinx, Asterisk, MySQL]

• Easy and efficient product and book search solution by which user can call in to our service online or via any regular telephone.

Assistant Systems Engineer at TCS

November 2008 - June 2009 (8 months)

• Positioned in a direct support role for Royal Bank of Scotland in the ongoing design and development of "Market Reference Data" project, which collates market data from various financial institutions on a daily basis.

• Implemented functionality to allow fragmenting, formatting and filtering of market data based on the specific requirements of individual clientele. [Shell script, Perl]

Education

Georgia Institute of Technology

MS, Information Security, 2009 - 2011

Pune Institute of Computer Technology

Bachelor's degree, Computer Science, 2004 - 2008

Fergusson College

HSC, 2002 - 2004

Honors and Awards

First prize at Convergence Innovation Competition 2011 at Georgia Tech, Facebook Hackathon at Georgia Tech, Concepts 2008

Vineet Patil

Software Engineer



Contact Vineet on LinkedIn